Guide to the Donna Lisker Papers, 1999-2014 UA.29.02.0243
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Donna Lisker papers
1999-2014
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Lisker, Donna
UA.29.02.0243
4.5 Linear Feet
525 Megabytes
Donna Lisker was the head of the Women's Center and Associate Dean for Undergraduate Education at Duke University in the 2000s and 2010s. The Donna Lisker Papers include materials on the development of the Baldwin Scholars Program, Lisker's service on the Women's Initiative and the President's Council on the Status of Women, retreats for women alumni of Duke, student housing, and other topics.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged into three series: Administrative Files, Baldwin Scholars Program, and Women's Initiative. Unprocessed materials related to the Women's Initiative have been placed in a fourth series.
Biographical / Historical
Donna Lisker served as the Director of the Women's Center and Associate Vice-Provost for Undergraduate Education at Duke University, and co-founded the Baldwin Scholars Program.
Donna Lisker recieved her B.A. in English from Williams College in 1988, and her Ph.D. in English from the University of Wisconsin-Madison in 1996. She became the Assistant Director of the Women's Center at Virginia Tech in 1995, and then came to Duke University in 1999 to serve as the Director of the Women's Center. She served on the steering committee of the Women's Initiative, a group that studied the place and status of women at the University, including students, faculty, and staff, and produced a report with recommendations for action, from 2001-2003. In 2004 she became one of the founders of the Baldwin Scholars Program, the four-year leadership program for undergraduate women at Duke, named for Alice Mary Baldwin, the first Dean of the Woman's College at Duke. She also served on the President's Commission on the Status of Women, also called the President's Council on Women, which implemented recommendations from the Women's Initiative report.
In 2007 Donna Lisker became an Associate Dean for Undergraduate Education, later an Associate Vice-Provost for Undergraduate Education. In this role she oversaw many aspects of undergraduate life, including housing and residential life and co-curricular activities such as the Winter Forum, and worked with Alumni Affairs on programs for women alumni such as the Women's Weekend. She was involved with strategic planning, including planning around the renovation of Central Campus. In 2013 she briefly served as the interim Vice Provost for Duke Kunshan University and China Initiative. Throughout her time at Duke, she taught courses in women's studies.
In 2014, Lisker was appointed the Dean of the College and Vice President for Campus Life at Smith College.
Conditions Governing Access
For a period of twenty-five years from the origin of the material, permission in writing from the office of origin and the University Archivist is required for use of administrative records. After twenty-five years, records that have been processed may be consulted with the permission of the University Archivist.
Conditions Governing Access
In accordance with the Family Education Rights and Privacy Act of 1974 as amended, Duke University permits students to inspect their education records and limits the disclosure of personally identifiable information from education records.
Conditions Governing Access
Electronic records in this collection have been migrated to a library server and digital use copies can only be accessed onsite in the Rubenstein Library Reading Room. To request access, please contact a reference archivist before coming to use these records.
Conditions Governing Access
Use of audiotapes and videotapes from this collection requires the creation of reference copies. Reference copies for some materials may have been made, and if a reference copy exists, it is noted in this finding aid. To arrange for the creation of reference copies of other items, please contact University Archives staff. Although these recordings are now stored in a stable environment, their condition and playback quality is unknown.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The Donna Lisker Papers were recieved by the Duke University Archives as a transfer in 2014 and 2019.
Related Materials
Baldwin Scholars Program Records, Duke University Archives, David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University.
Women's Center Records, Duke University Archives, David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University.
Susan Roth Papers, Duke University Archives, David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University.
Scope and Contents
The Donna Lisker Papers include materials from Lisker's work with the Baldwin Scholars Program, on the Steering Committee of the Women's Initiative, and as Associate Vice-Provost for Undergraduate Education. Topics covered include planning and development of the Baldwin Scholars Program, particularly in correspondence with Jean O'Barr, research and reports from the Women's Initiative and follow-up committees, Lisker's work with Alumni Affairs, planning of Central Campus/New Campus, retreats for and outreach to women alumni, curriculum and budget planning for the Baldwin Scholars Program, and other subjects. Included are correspondence, reports, research, budget documents, and other materials.
Women college teachers -- North Carolina -- Durham; Women college students -- North Carolina -- Durham; Women college administrators -- North Carolina -- Durham; Lisker, Donna; Duke University. Baldwin Scholars Program; Duke University. Alumni Association; O'Barr, Jean F.; Duke University -- Administration
- Administrative Files, 1994-2012; 1 Linear Feet
  Conditions Governing Access
  For a period of twenty-five years from the origin of the material, permission in writing from the office of origin and the University Archivist is required for use of administrative records. After twenty-five years, records that have been processed may be consulted with the permission of the University Archivist.
  Scope and Contents
  This series primarily consists of materials from Donna Lisker's time as Associate Vice Provost for Undergraduate Education. Included are materials related to retreats, workshops, and outreach efforts for women alumni coordinated with Alumni Affairs; planning for renovations and housing changes to Central Campus, also referred to as New Campus; strategic planning; student housing; the Winter Forum speaker program; and other topics. Files include correspondence, brochures, flyers, reports, and other materials.
  - AAC&U (Association of American Colleges and Universities), 2009 (Box 1)
    Restricted until 2034
  - AAC&U (Association of American Colleges and Universities), 2010 (Box 1)
    Restricted until 2035
  - Academics, circa 2008-2014 (Digital-materials UA29020243-SET-0001)
    Restricted until 2039.
  - Admissions, circa 2008-2014 (Digital-materials UA29020243-SET-0001)
  - Advising, circa 2008-2014 (Digital-materials UA29020243-SET-0001)
  - Alcohol, circa 2008-2014 (Digital-materials UA29020243-SET-0001)
  - Alumni Affairs, circa 2008-2014 (Digital-materials UA29020243-SET-0001)
  - Assessment, circa 2008-2014 (Digital-materials UA29020243-SET-0001)
  - Athletics, circa 2008-2014 (Digital-materials UA29020243-SET-0001)
  - Board of Trustees, circa 2008-2014 (Digital-materials UA29020243-SET-0002)
    Restricted until 2064.
  - Central Campus, 2009 (Box 1)
  - Central Campus Residential Groups, 2009 (Box 1)
  - Chicago [Women's Forum], spring 2012 (Box 1)
    Restricted until 2037
  - COFHE, circa 2008-2014 (Digital-materials UA29020243-SET-0001)
  - DCCE, circa 2008-2014 (Digital-materials UA29020243-SET-0001)
    Restricted until 2084.
  - Development, circa 2008-2014 (Digital-materials UA29020243-SET-0001)
  - Dining, 2008-2009 (Box 1)
  - DL, circa 2008-2014 (Digital-materials UA29020243-SET-0001)
  - Duke Conversations, 2009-2010 (Box 1)
  - Duke Immerse, circa 2008-2014 (Digital-materials UA29020243-SET-0001)
  - Duke Social Relationships Project Meeting 10/28/08, 2008-2009 (Box 1)
  - Duke Student Government Task Force on Financial Aid: Financial Aid Report, 31 July 2000 (Box 1)
    Restricted until 2025
  - Financial Aid, circa 2008-2014 (Digital-materials UA29020243-SET-0001)
  - Financial Aid Project, 2004 (Box 1)
    Restricted until 2029
  - FLUNCH, circa 2008-2014 (Digital-materials UA29020243-SET-0001)
  - Gates Scholars, circa 2008-2014 (Digital-materials UA29020243-SET-0001)
  - Governance, circa 2008-2014 (Digital-materials UA29020243-SET-0001)
  - Institutional Equity, 2009 (Box 1)
  - Internationalization, circa 2008-2014 (Digital-materials UA29020243-SET-0001)
  - Andrea LaRue, 1994 (Box 1)
  - Majors Unions, 2008 (Box 1)
    Restricted until 2033
  - MIT Report, 1999 (Box 1)
  - Money, Sex, & Power [Alumnae Weekend], 2009 (Box 1)
  - Moxie Conference [Women's Weekend], 2014 (Box 1)
    Restricted until 2039
  - NASPA Leadership, 2008 (Box 1)
  - New Campus, circa 2008-2014 (Digital-materials UA29020243-SET-0001)
  - New Campus: Student Feedback, 2008 (Box 1)
  - New Campus, 2008 (Box 1)
  - New Campus: Student Service Space, 2008 (Box 1)
  - New Campus: Draft Design Guidelines, July 2008 (Box 1)
  - New Campus: Housing Plans, 2008 (Box 1)
  - Old House Model, 2008-2009 (Box 1)
  - Orientation, circa 2008-2014 (Digital-materials UA29020243-SET-0001)
  - OUSF, circa 2008-2014 (Digital-materials UA29020243-SET-0002)
  - OWW (Orientation Welcome Week) Advisory Committee, 2007-2010 (Box 1)
  - Pass/Fail, 2008-2010 (Box 1)
  - Presentations, circa 2008-2014 (Digital-materials UA29020243-SET-0001)
  - QEP, circa 2008-2014 (Digital-materials UA29020243-SET-0001)
  - Reinvention Conference, 2008 (Box 1)
  - Residential Life, circa 2008-2014 (Digital-materials UA29020243-SET-0001)
  - Senior Survey, 2007 (Box 1)
    Restricted until 2032
  - St. Bernard Project, 2008 (Box 1)
  - Strategic Plan 2005-2006: Undergrad Experience, 2006-2007, 2011 (Box 1)
    Restricted until 2036
  - Strategic Plan/University, 2005 (Box 1)
    Restricted until 2030
  - Strategic Planning, 2010-2012 (Digital-materials UA29020243-SET-0002)
    Restricted until 2082.
  - Student Affairs, 2009-2012 (Digital-materials UA29020243-SET-0002)
  - Student Initiatives, circa 2008-2014 (Digital-materials UA29020243-SET-0001)
  - Summer Reading, 2008-2013 (Box 1)
    Restricted until 2038
  - Teaching Innovation, circa 2008-2014 (Digital-materials UA29020243-SET-0001)
  - Underload Proposal, 2007-2008 (Box 1)
  - University Leadership Committee, 2008 (Box 1)
  - ULG, circa 2008-2014 (Digital-materials UA29020243-SET-0001)
  - Website, circa 2008-2014 (Digital-materials UA29020243-SET-0001)
  - West Union, 2007, 2011 (Box 1)
  - West Union, circa 2008-2014 (Digital-materials UA29020243-SET-0001)
  - WILL Replication, October 1999 (Box 1)
    Restricted until 2024
  - Winning Women [Women's Weekend], 2012 (Box 1)
  - Winter Forum 2010, 2009-2010 (Box 1)
  - Winter Forum 2011, 2010-2011 (Box 1)
  - Winter Forum 2012, 2011-2012 (Box 1)
  - Winter Forum, circa 2008-2014 (Digital-materials UA29020243-SET-0001)
  - Women's Summit, 2009 (Box 1)
- Baldwin Scholars Program, 2003-2012 and undated; 0.5 Linear Feet
  This series includes materials related to the Baldwin Scholars Program, especially its early development. Included are materials related to program parameters and structure; courses and curriculum; budget and funding, including fundraising; student scholars; planning; staff; and many other topics. Files include correspondence, reports, budgets, and other materials. Jean Fox O'Barr, co-director of the Program, is a frequent correspondent.
  - BSP Constitution, 2006 (Box 2)
    Restricted until 2031
  - Class of 2008, 2005-2006 (Box 2)
  - Class of 2009, 2009, undated (Box 2)
  - Class of 2010, 2006, undated (Box 2)
  - Class of 2011, 2007, 2011 (Box 2)
  - Class of 2012, circa 2008 (Box 2)
  - Upperclass Affiliates, 2004 (Box 2)
  - BSP Program Review, Fall 2008 (Box 2)
  - Baldwin Internships, 2003-2005 (Box 2)
  - Baldwin Scholars Advisory Board Final Report, 2008-2009 (Box 2)
  - Baldwin Assessment, 2004-2010 (Box 2)
  - Duke Endowment Reports, 2006-2009 (Box 2)
  - Baldwin Retreat, 2009 (Box 2)
  - Baldwin Scholars/Programmatic, 2004-2005 (Box 2)
  - Baldwin Commencement, 2008 (Box 2)
  - Duke Magazine story, 2005, 2007 (Box 2)
    Digital materials in this folder are a copy of the student documentary Alice Baldwin and the Durhamites; not all contents of this folder are available in digital format.
  - Atlantis MS, undated (Box 2)
  - CAPE: Henry Friedman, 2005 (Box 2)
  - Mother-Daughter Weekend, April 2008 (Box 2)
  - Mother-Daughter, 2012 (Box 2)
  - Baldwin budget, 2004-2008 (Box 2)
  - Baldwin Ast. Dir. Search, 2004 (Box 2)
  - Administrative & Personnel, 2003-2010 (Box 2)
  - Website, 2007-2008 (Box 2)
  - Advisory Board, 2004-2009 (Box 2)
  - Marketing & Recruitment, 2004-2006 (Box 2)
    Digital materials in this folder are a poster for the Baldwin Scholars Program; not all contents of this folder are available in digital format.
  - Correspondence: Development, 2003-2008 (Box 2)
  - Fundraising, 2004-2005 (Box 2)
  - Fundraising Dinner NYC, 12 October 2006 (Box 2)
  - Baldwin Curriculum Committee, 2004-2005 (Box 2)
  - Baldwin Proposal & Initial Planning, 2003 (Box 2)
    Restricted until 2028
  - Senior Seminar, 2006-2007, undated (Box 2)
  - SOC 49S, Spring 2005 (Box 2)
  - SOC 90S, Spring 2006 (Box 2)
  - SOC 90S, Spring 2007 (Box 2)
  - SOC 90S, Spring 2008 (Box 2)
  - SOC 90S, Spring 2009 (Box 2)
  - SOC 90S Evaluations, 2011-2012, undated (Box 2)
  - Effortless Perfection MS, 2006 (Box 2)
  - Sophomore Seminar, 2009, undated (Box 2)
  - Program Review, undated (Box 2)
  - Upperclass Affiliates, 2005 (Box 2)
    Restricted until 2075
  - Autobiography Readings, undated (Box 2)
  - Administration, circa 2008-2014 (Digital-materials UA29020243-SET-0001)
  - Alumnae donors, circa 2008-2014 (Digital-materials UA29020243-SET-0001)
  - Baldwin Pics, circa 2008-2014 (Digital-materials UA29020243-SET-0001)
  - Budget, 2004-2011 (Digital-materials UA29020243-SET-0002)
    Restricted until 2081.
  - CAPE, circa 2008-2014 (Digital-materials UA29020243-SET-0001)
  - Proposals, 2004-2010 (Digital-materials UA29020243-SET-0001)
    Restricted until 2035.
  - Scholarship, 2007-2009, undated (Digital-materials UA29020243-SET-0001)
    Restricted until 2034.
- Women's Initiative, 2001-2007; 0.25 Linear Feet
  This series includes materials related to Lisker's participation in the Women's Initiative Steering Committee, the President's Commission on the Status of Women, and the President's Council on Women. Files include correspondence, reports, research, and other materials.
  - Women's Steering Committee binder, 2001-2003; 3 folders (Box 2)
  - President's Commission on the Status of Women binder, 2004-2006; 3 folders (Box 2)
  - President's Council on Women, 2006-2007 (Box 2)
  - Women's Initiative audio recordings, 2002-2003 and undated (Box 3)
    FERPA restricted until 2072.
    Recordings of interview sessions with groups of women during the research phase of the Women's Initiative.
  - Womens Initiative, 2002-2008 (Digital-materials UA29020243-SET-0001)
    Restricted until 2033.
  - Women's Initiative Follow-Up, 2004-2013 (Digital-materials UA29020243-SET-0001)
    Restricted until 2038.
- Accession UA2019.0054: Women's Initiative materials, circa 2002-2004
  Materials in this series have not been processed and must be screened for restricted materials before use.
  - Untitled Folder, circa 2002-2004 (Box 4)
    These materials need additional screening for restricted materials before use.
  - Media Response, circa 2002-2004 (Box 4)
  - Report Drafts, circa 2002-2004 (Box 4)
  - SA Gender Study, circa 2002-2004 (Box 4)
  - Surveys, circa 2002-2004 (Box 4)
  - Effortless Perfection book, circa 2002-2004 (Box 4)
  - Kimberly Jenkins, circa 2002-2004 (Box 4)
  - Alumnae Letters, circa 2002-2004 (Box 4)
  - Wisconsin Rollout, Spring 2004 (Box 4)
  - Committee on Women's Leadership, circa 2002-2004 (Box 4)
  - Alumnae Volunteer Lists, circa 2002-2004 (Box 4)
  - Sexual Assault Report, circa 2002-2004 (Box 4)
  - Philanthrophy and Leadership, circa 2002-2004 (Box 4)
  - Los Angeles Alumnae FG, circa 2002-2004 (Box 4)
  - San Francisco Sign In, circa 2002-2004 (Box 4)
  - Triangle Focus Groups, circa 2002-2004 (Box 4)
  - Atlanta, circa 2002-2004 (Box 4)
  - Chicago Focus Groups, circa 2002-2004 (Box 4)
  - Washington DC Alumnae FGs, circa 2002-2004 (Box 4)
  - New York City Focus Group, circa 2002-2004 (Box 4)
  - Gender Initiative IRB, circa 2002-2004 (Box 4)
  - Alumnae Focus Groups, circa 2002-2004 (Box 4)
  - NOK's Initiative for Women, 2002 (Box 4)
  - Fall Focus Groups, circa 2002-2004 (Box 4)
  - Spring Focus Groups, circa 2002-2004 (Box 4)
  - Gender Initiative: Student, circa 2002-2004 (Box 4)
  - Student Focus Groups, circa 2002-2004 (Box 4)
  - Duke Gender Initiative Task Force, circa 2002-2004 (Box 4)